<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Newsletter | Amp Knob]]></title>
  <link href="http://ampknob.com/blog/categories/newsletter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ampknob.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-25T21:19:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ampknob.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Shane Rice]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AmpKnob Newsletter: September 25, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://ampknob.com/blog/newsletter-september-25/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-25T20:34:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ampknob.com/blog/newsletter-september-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, campers, rise and shine, don&rsquo;t forget to read AmpKnob this week!</p>

<p>I took a big part of this week off to enjoy Walt Disney World with the family, but getting home on Sunday night gives me plenty of time to get this to your inbox for Monday morning.</p>

<p>Do you want to keep getting this delivered on Sunday night for you to read on Monday morning? Email newsletters normally get sent after the crush of the Monday morning inbox, but since this newsletter should have tidbits you can fit into your work for the week it makes sense to send it now.</p>

<p>If you want it at a different time, can you send me an email? I can setup some personalization for delivery times, but I don&rsquo;t want to spend time doing that if no one is interested.</p>

<p>Now, on to the news.</p>

<h2>People remember branded content when they forget ads</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.ipglab.com/2016/09/23/ipg-media-lab-forbes-evaluate-the-current-state-of-branded-content/">IPG MediaLab released a study this week showing people recall branded content 59% more than other display ads</a>. The results are similar to a study from 2013.</p>

<p>This is kind of incredible stuff.</p>

<p>We should all be thinking through ways to pay to have our best content setup as branded content in the right publications.</p>

<h2>Egg all over Facebook for video metric error</h2>

<p>Facebook announced an error in one of their video metrics this week. If you saw this story at all, the headlines discussed it with breathless headlines.</p>

<p>Businessweek said, &ldquo;Facebook says it gave advertisers inflated video metrics!&rdquo;</p>

<p>David Fischer, from Facebook, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/fischer/posts/10157497355045187">shared a post where he clarified exactly what Facebook miscalculated</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;About a month ago, we found an error in the way we calculate one of the video metrics on our dashboard – average duration of video viewed. The metric should have reflected the total time spent watching a video divided by the total number of people who played the video. But it didn’t – it reflected the total time spent watching a video divided by only the number of “views” of a video (that is, when the video was watched for three or more seconds). And so the miscalculation overstated this metric. While this is only one of the many metrics marketers look at, we take any mistake seriously.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Facebook video ads are super cheap, somewhere around $.01 for many advertisers, so I&rsquo;d take this story with a grain of salt and continue to experiment with Facebook ads.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t go spending your entire marketing budget on Facebook, but test to see if you can find a cheap method to get in front of your target audience.</p>

<h2>Media links don&rsquo;t count against character limits on Twitter now</h2>

<p>While we&rsquo;re talking about social media stories, <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/express-even-more-in-140-characters">back in May Twitter announced</a> they&rsquo;d stop counting media links against the character limit for tweets.</p>

<p>This feature has fully rolled out now. This doesn&rsquo;t extend the limit for links to posts outside of Twitter, but does change the rules for Retweets so you can RT a reply to all of your followers instead of using &lsquo;.@&rsquo; to broadcast.</p>

<h2>Reflik geohacks TechCrunch Disrupt. TechCrunch is pissed!</h2>

<p>This story made me laugh pretty hard.</p>

<p>TechCrunch Disrupt was in SF. In the immortal words of Fred Armisen as Joy Behar, &ldquo;So what? Who cares?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Well, Reflik snapped up a Snapchat geofilter to cover the spot where the event was being held for $58. So, attendees who paid $2,995 per ticket were getting hit with an ad for a product they could use on Snapchat for peanuts.</p>

<p>A TechCrunch writer took to his keyboard to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/23/the-biggest-problem-with-snapchats-geofilter-product/">call for Snapchat to open up a bidding system for their geofilters</a>. It all read as a bit of sour grapes on the part of TechCrunch, and I frankly loved the hustle of Reflik figuring out how to get the word out on the cheap.</p>

<h2>Spotify and Tinder team up to power matches</h2>

<p><a href="https://news.spotify.com/us/2016/09/20/spotify-partners-with-tinder-to-swipe-up-the-volume/">Spotify announced they&rsquo;re going to help people decide if they want to connect on Tinder</a>. Once they opt-in, folks using Tinder can now see artists you have in common, pick an &lsquo;Anthem&rsquo; to share on Tinder, and view other people&rsquo;s Anthems on their profile.</p>

<p>The interesting thing about this announcement is Spotify is spreading their data out to other apps to make interesting connections based on listening habits. There&rsquo;s a ton of untapped potential for music preferences and apps to crossover and provide a better experience to both sets of users.</p>

<h2>Share AmpKnob?</h2>

<p>This is the end of the second week of the AmpKnob newsletter. Have the last two weeks helped you keep up with marketing news you might&rsquo;ve missed without it?</p>

<p>If it has, it&rsquo;d mean the world to me if you could share it with your friends on Twitter or Facebook. I&rsquo;m going to keep the goodness coming, and have a few special projects you&rsquo;ll hear more about over the next couple of months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AmpKnob Newsletter: September 18, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://ampknob.com/blog/newsletter-september-18/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-18T18:58:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ampknob.com/blog/newsletter-september-18</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first edition of the AmpKnob newsletter and there&rsquo;s still a ton I&rsquo;m figuring out. I&rsquo;d love to hear what you think of these stories, the format, pretty much anything. My goal is to make every week better than the last, and your thoughts will help make that goal a reality.</p>

<p>You signed up for a brand new newsletter with complete faith in me, and I take that really seriously. Thank you.</p>

<p>And now, on to the stories.</p>

<h2>Changes coming for mobile search results</h2>

<p>Back in August, Google announced a few big changes for mobile search users.</p>

<p>First, Google started using mobile-friendliness as a positive ranking factor in April 2015. Pages from mobile-friendly websites got a nice little tag in their Search Engine Results Page. Google said this update only impacts searches made on mobile devices, which means basically means there have been at least two indexes people can use to find your site. One for mobile searches and one for desktop searches.</p>

<p>Then in August, <a href="https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2016/08/helping-users-easily-access-content-on.html">Google announced a couple of new changes for mobile search</a>. First, they will be dropping the mobile friendly tag in search results on mobile devices. They&rsquo;ve said that 85% of search results now meet their mobile friendly criteria.</p>

<p>Which is kind of like having a pie contest, giving an advantage to square pies, and then being surprised when 85% of people show up with square pies. Google waves their hands, but this is no magic trick.</p>

<p>The second change is a penalty for sites showing full page interstitials to mobile visitors. Since many sites use responsive elements, this change will also have an impact beyond mobile.</p>

<p>This penalty goes into effect January 10, 2017 so if you (or someone you know) are using interstitials to collect email addresses be sure to turn those off before this deadline.</p>

<h2>Shane&rsquo;s Google prediction corner</h2>

<p><strong>Prediction 1: Google will consolidate their indexes.</strong> I mentioned Google has pretty much admitted to running to unique indexes for mobile and desktop searches, and over the next two years my guess is we&rsquo;ll see them consolidate this back to one as mobile traffic continues to gain ground.</p>

<p><strong>Prediction 2: Google will incentivize dates on blog posts.</strong> Google has the power to improve user experience across the web, and I think in the next couple of year we&rsquo;ll see them find a way to encourage people to include a visible publication date on their blog posts. SEOs using this as a trick to appear evergreen are going to attract the Google&rsquo;s gaze and get this trend relegated to the scrap heap of bad UX.</p>

<h2>Set support hours for your Twitter handle</h2>

<p>Twitter announced this week they&rsquo;re going to let products set availability for their handles. You can mark your account as a &lsquo;Support Account&rsquo; and set support hours in your settings.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/YGr6EXA.png" alt="Set Support account on Twitter" /></p>

<h2>AdBlock Plus gets skeezy</h2>

<p>AdBlock Plus made it&rsquo;s name by blocking ads for users and this week courted controversy as they announced plans to test a programmatic ad platform within their Acceptable Ads program.</p>

<p>AdWeek reported Sridhar Ramaswamy, SVP of ads and commerce at Google, told reporters at the DMEXCO conference in Germany on Wednesday that Adblock Plus “erects toll booths on a public road and siphons off advertising dollars that should be going directly to publishers."</p>

<p>People block ads because their intrusive and ad platforms are abused by scammers. Company makes money by offering to block ads for free with a premium upgrade edition, and sells ads to people who use their free edition. Shakedown city.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Would be a shame if these perfectly nice ads started showing up in your browser again.&rdquo;</p>

<h2>Brian Dean at SumoCon</h2>

<p>I had a chance to attend SumoCon, and was floored by Brian Dean&rsquo;s presentation. Reading <a href="http://backlinko.com">Backlinko</a> can feel like trying to drink from a fire hydrant sometimes, <a href="http://backlinko.com/on-page-seo">so hit this link and CMD+F &lsquo;Sprinkle LSI Keywords&rsquo; to read his tip on how to find Latent Semantic Indexed keywords to sprinkle into your posts</a>.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s really, really good. I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ll be seeing many more tips from Brian on AmpKnob.</p>

<h2>Tweets you shouldn&rsquo;t miss</h2>

<p>Brandon Mathis pointed out you can <a href="https://twitter.com/imathis/status/776850598608171008">manage updates to apps in iOS 10 with Force press</a>.</p>

<p>Scott Kerr shared an email chain between LEGO and a 7 year-old who lost a minifigure. <a href="https://twitter.com/scott_kerr/status/776752757894184960">It&rsquo;s the kind of customer support story you hope your kid encounters</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
